Guide to the Blackman Company sales training memoranda, 1924-1928 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Blackman Company sales training memoranda 1924-1928 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Blackman Company
0.6 Linear Feet 30 Items
Blackman Company was an advertising company founded in 1908 by Oscar H. Blackman and Frank Hermes. Became Compton Advertising in 1937.
Collection comprises a series of 30 memoranda written by company staff. Training topics address various aspects of the marketing process, as well as advertising for regional or specialized consumer markets, including the "modern woman."
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Blackman Company sales training memoranda were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Historical Note
Blackman Company was an advertising company founded in 1908 by Oscar H. Blackman and Frank Hermes. Became Compton Advertising in 1937.
Collection comprises a series of memoranda written by company staff. Training topics address various aspects of the marketing process, as well as advertising for regional or specialized consumer markets, including the "modern woman." Other topics include selling through contests, sampling, and installment plans, in addition to department or chain stores, grocers, and outdoor advertsing; advertsing copy, teams, budgets, and costs; packaging; newspaper advertising; trademarks; the use of artwork; and salesmens' education and pay. There are also research reports, as well as an address by M. L. Wilson on industrial advertsing. The memoranda were housed in a binder, and there are tabbed dividers that provide the titles of each piece; many also feature a list of companies for whom Blackman worked or a list of staff writers for the series. It is unclear whether the material was meant for in-house use only. There are copywrite symbols that may indicate that the material was available to train those outside the company as well. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Wilson, M. L.
Blackman Company
Compton Advertising, inc.--History
Advertising agencies -- United States
Advertising
Department stores
Advertising -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.
Advertising, Newspaper -- United States
Advertising, Outdoor -- United States
Advertising -- United States
Advertising -- United States -- Costs
Advertising -- United States -- Finance
Advertising copy
Installment plan -- United States
Sales management
Sales personnel -- Training of -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.
Sales promotion -- United States -- History
Show windows
Selling -- Competitions
Selling -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.
Selling -- Instructional materials
Trademarks -- Design
Women consumers
Detailed Description of Collection
- Memoranda, 1924, (10 folders)
  - An advertising survey of the farm market (Box 1)
  - Art with an advertising accent
  - Business press: A primer to start advertisers' and advertising agencies' thinking
  - Copy-culture: A suggestive source-book for the advertiser of manufactured products
  - How shall we pay our salesmen?
  - Outdoor advertising: Some factors to consider
  - Practical economies in preparing advertisements
  - Securing sales thru store display--economically
  - Selling to and through chain stores
  - What basis for the advertising appropriation?
- Memoranda, 1925, (6 folders)
  - Packaging to sell (Box 1)
  - Salesmen's prize contests: Plans--Cautions--Suggestions
  - Sampling to sell
  - Selling to Canada
  - Teamwork: Making selling advertise--making advertising sell
  - What the newspaper offers the national advertiser
- Memoranda, 1926, (5 folders)
  - Customer copy: A point of view (Box 1)
  - Educating salesmen
  - Introducing New England to the national advertisers
  - The new geography of distribution
  - Selling through the installment plan
- Memoranda, 1927, (4 folders)
  - Copy's increasing competition: Ways to meet it (Box 1)
  - The high cost of rush in advertising
  - Selling to and through department stores
  - Trade-marks: How to make them valuable
- Memoranda, 1928 and undated, (5 folders)
  - Modern art in industry: An attempt to find out if we should point with pride or view with alarm (Box 1)
  - Selling the Browns, the Smiths, and the Joneses through grocers
  - Selling the modern woman
  - A picture of eating habits
  - Application of imagination to industrial advertising: An address.... by M. L. Wilson